[MUSIC]
[음악]
One of the most common types of classifiers is a so
분류기에서 가장 흔한 종류는
called linear classifier.
선형 분류기입니다
So let's talk a little bit about that.
이에 대해 조금 알아보도록 하죠
The question here is how do we represent the classifier?
분류기를 어떻게 나타낼 것인지가 문제입니다
So we start with some sentences, for example in a sentiment the mouse's case,
예를 들어 감성분석에서 특정 문장을 가져다
the classifier.
분류기에 넣어주면
You get a prediction whether it is a positive sentence or a negative sentence.
긍정적인 문장인지 부정적인 문장인지 예측이 반환됩니다
So, how does this classifier work?
분류기가 어떻게 작동하지요?
In the sentimental analysis you can imagine a simple
감성분석에서 간단한 역치 분류기를
kind of threshold classifier.
떠올려 보죠
Suppose that I take a sentence and somebody tells me
문장과 함께
these are all of the positive words, great, awesome, good amazing and so on.
대단하다, 굉장하다, 좋다, 놀랍다 등 온갖 종류의 긍적적인 단어가 주어집니다
Here's a bunch of negative words.
부정적인 단어도 주어집니다
Bad, terrible, disgusting, food, and so on.
별로다, 끔찍하다, 역겹다 등등
And so what I can do is take the sentence and
그리고 나서 문장에
count how many positive words there are in a sentence and
긍정적인 단어와 부정적인 단어가
how many negative words are in the sentence, just count those.
몇 개씩 있는지 셉니다
And then say if the number of positive words is higher
그리고 긍정적인 단어가
than the number of negative words.
부정적인 단어보다 많으면
Then we have a positive sentence but
긍정적인 문장이고
if they use more negative more words then you have a negative sentence.
부정적인 단어가 많으면 부정적인 문장입니다
So for example, if the input sentence that we have is the sushi was great positive
입력 문장, 초밥이 훌륭했다는 긍정이니 +1
one, the food was awesome positive two, but the service was terrible negative one.
음식이 굉장했다 +2 서비스는 최악이었다 -1.
You have two positives one negative and
+2에 -1이니
in the end was the positive wins and so you have a positive prediction.
합은 긍정이고 긍정적인 예측을 나타냅니다
Now threshold classifiers have some limitations.
역치 분류기에는 한계도 있습니다
Where does this list of positive and negative words actually come from?
긍정적, 부정적 단어 목록이 어디서 나왔죠?
It has to magically come from somewhere and
어디선가 마법처럼 나타났는데다
not just that, words have different degrees of positive and negativeness.
단어의 긍정과 부정에는 정도가 있습니다
So great is more positive than good.
훌륭하다는 좋다보다 긍정적입니다
You wanna tune and figure out what's better great, good, amazing,
훌륭하다, 좋다, 굉장하다 사이에서
is amazing better than great?
굉장하다가 훌륭하다보다 낫나요?
Who knows?
앞으로 어떻게 될지는 모르니까요
So how do we figure that out, how do we weigh different words?
그걸 어떻게 알아내고, 서로 다른 단어에 어떤 가중치를 주나요?
And single words might not be enough to make good classification.
단어 하나만으론 제대로 된 분류를 하기 충분하지 않을 수 있습니다
So good food, so the food was good is positive.
좋은 음식, 음식은 좋았다는 긍정입니다
The food was not good is actually negative.
하지만 음식이 좋지 않았다는 부정이죠
And so these are all issues that need to be addressed.
이런 문제들을 처리해야 합니다
The first two areas where the positive and negative words come from and
긍정, 부정적인 단어가 어디서 오는지와
how do you weigh them comes from learning a classifier and
가중치 정하는 법은 분류기를 학습함으로써
we're going to talk about next.
익힐 수 있는데 다음으로 설명하죠
The issue of good versus not good
좋다 나쁘다의 문제는 단어 하나보다
is addressed by using more complicated features than single words.
복잡한 특징을 사용함으로써 해결합니다
And we're gonna talk about it towards the end of the module.
이 모듈 끝 무렵에 설명합니다
So a linear classifier, instead of having a list of positive and
선형 분류기는 긍정적, 부정적인 단어 목록만
negative words, actually takes all the words and adds weights to them.
아니라 가중치를 부여합니다
So, for example, good might have a weight of 1, great might have a weight of 1.5,
예를 들어 좋다는 가중치 1, 훌륭하다는 가중치 1.5,
awesome might have really big weight of 2.7.
굉장하다는 높은 가중치 2.7입니다
While bad might have a weight of -1, terrible may have a weight of -2.1,
나쁘다는 가중치 -1, 최악이다는 가중치 -2.1
awful might be -3.3 cuz awful is really just awful.
끔찍하다는 -3.3쯤 될 거 같은데 끔찍한 건 정말 끔찍하기 때문이죠
And this ways that really don't matter to sentiment.
감성과 관계 없는 단어도 있는데
So things like the, we, where, restaurant, they appear both in positive and
우리, 장소, 레스토랑 같은 단어는 긍정, 부정적인
negative sentences so they get weight zero.
문장에 모두 출현하기 때문에 가중치가 0입니다
Suppose somebody magically told you what the weight of each word were.
누군가 각 단어의 가중치가 얼만지 전부 알려줬다고 칩시다
We're going to talk about it in a little bit how those get learned
나중에 분류기가 이를 어떻게 학습하는지
by the classifier.
배울 겁니다
But given those weight, how to figure out if the sentence is positive or negative.
가중치가 주어졌을 때 문장이 긍정인지 부정인지 어떻게 알아낼까요?
Here we use the idea of scoring.
점수 채점이란 개념을 도입합니다
So for example take this sentence.
예를 들어 이 문장을 보죠
The sushi was great, the food was awesome, but the service was terrible.
초밥은 훌륭했다, 음식은 굉장했다, 하지만 서비스는 최악이었다.
Let's score that sentence.
이 문장의 점수를 매겨보죠
So we're gonna compute this, the score of the input sentence x.
입력 문장 x의 점수를 계산합니다
So in this case, you get from great, you get positive 1.2.
훌륭하다 +1.2
From awesome, you get another 1.7 but
굉장하다 1.7
from table, you get minus 2.1 right here,
최악이다 -2.1
and so the grand total here is 2.9 minus 2.1, which is 0.8.
총합은 2.9-2.1, 0.8이죠
And the key here is that since the score of the sentence is greater than zero,
중요한 점은 문장의 점수가 0보다 크니
we're going to predict that it is a positive sentence.
긍정적인 문장이라고 예측한다는 것입니다
If the score was the opposite, if the score of x were less than zero,
반대로 0보다 작다면
then we'd have predicted it's a negative sentence.
부정적인 문장이라고 예측했겠죠
So this is how a linear classifier works,
선형 분류기의 작동방식입니다
if you know the weight of each word, and this is called
각 단어의 가중치를 알면 되는데
a linear classifier because the output is basically the weighted sum of the input.
선형 분류기가 불리는 이유는 결과물이 기본적으로 입력의 가중치 합이기 때문입니다
Just weight, what features appears, what words appear in the input.
입력에서 어떤 특징, 단어가 나타나는지 세기만 하면 됩니다
So we're working for simple linear classifier to start out with.
간단한 선형 분류기를 알아봤습니다
So in summary, given a sentence and given the weights for
요약하자면 문장과 문장의 가중치가 주어졌을 때
the sentence, what we do is compute the score,
문장에 등장하는 단어의 가중치 합인
which is the weighted count of the words that appear in the sentence.
점수를 계산합니다
And then we say if the score is greater than zero,
점수가 0보다 크다면
we predict y-hat to be positive.
y^은 긍정적입니다
While if the score is less than zero, we predict it to be negative.
점수가 0보다 작으면 부정적이라고 예측합니다
And that is a linear classifier.
선형 분류기에 대해 알아봤습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]